KAREM CERON

☐ 917-679-9702 karemiceron@gmail.com

• FULL STACK DEVELOPER •

Github · LinkedIn · Website

Astoria, NY, 11106

PROFILE

Full-Stack Developer with experience building apps in React, Redux, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. Strong skills in communication, organization and collaboration. Fluent in English and Spanish. Passionate community service volunteer dedicated to relieving hunger and improving public spaces in underserved communities.

SKILLS

React/Redux, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Sinatra, Active Record, Git/Github, SQL and PostgreSQL,

PROJECTS

PRONTO MEAL

Share your own quick meal creations that turn out to be delicious

- Used Session based authorization to store encrypted user information.
- Constructed a React Front end and a Back end with Rails as a JSON API.
- Designed Front end views utilizing vanilla CSS.
- Used Cloudinary as an API.

ARTE LUZ

Get inspired by art and share your own

- Collaboration with a cohort friend helped this project come to life.
- Users can look at other peoples' art and their own, similar to Instagram.
- Languages used: JavaScript, Ruby on Rails as an API and custom CSS.

JAMMIN

Create music playlists and share them with your friends

- Collaborating with a class partner made this project possible.
- Used custom CSS to style.
- Utilized Ruby and Ruby on Rails for Front and Back end.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL

Software Engineering

Brooklyn, NY (06/2020 - 10/2020)

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

NY SCHOOL FOR MEDICAL AND DENTAL ASSISTANTS

Evening Program - Dental Assistant

Queens, NY (07/2016 - 07/2017)

Dental Assistant Certificate

EXPERIENCE

SABBATICAL

Teaching myself how to program

Queens, NY (11/2019 - 05/2020)

• I taught myself to program in preparation for the bootcamp at Flatiron School,

DENTAL ASSISTANT

Hello Smile Pediatric Dental

Queens, NY (07/2017 - 11/2019)

 Assisted Dentists and Surgeons in a variety of dental procedures at locations in underserved communities. Taking over customer service responsibilities such as calling in patients, getting their medical history. Keeping materials inventory as well as being in contact with providers, placing orders. Submitting, tracking and receiving laboratory orders from dental technicians.